<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>computational fluid dynamics on Asphota Wasti</title>
    <link>https://asphota.github.io/tags/computational-fluid-dynamics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in computational fluid dynamics on Asphota Wasti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:18:40 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asphota.github.io/tags/computational-fluid-dynamics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How much does coastal flood depend on the topographic features?</title>
      <link>https://asphota.github.io/blog/topographic_sensitivity_storm_surge_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:18:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asphota.github.io/blog/topographic_sensitivity_storm_surge_model/</guid>
      <description>Application of Hydroinformatics: Topographic Sensitivity in Storm Surge Modeling The National Water Center organizes Summer Institute  every year which is a partnership between CUAHSI and the National Weather Service to engage the academic community in research to advance the mission of the National Water Center.
I participated in the Summer Institute in 2021 and worked with the Hydroinformatics cohort. It was intense but one of the most intersting projects I have done so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How vulnerable is our water supply to climate change?</title>
      <link>https://asphota.github.io/blog/multidimensional_risk_assessment_rank_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:18:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asphota.github.io/blog/multidimensional_risk_assessment_rank_model/</guid>
      <description>Vulnerability assessment of drinking water supply under climate uncertainty using a river contamination risk (RANK) model The contamination in the river can enter the water supply system and pollute the drinking water. In this study, a framework was developed to demonstrate the application of a Computational Fluid Dynamics model in risk assessment of contamination exposure in surface waters. This model aims to address the limitations of current water quality models by establishing a two-dimensional finite volume based model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
