<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>risk assessment on Asphota Wasti</title>
    <link>https://asphota.github.io/tags/risk-assessment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in risk assessment on Asphota Wasti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:18:40 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asphota.github.io/tags/risk-assessment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change Risk Assessment of a hydropower project</title>
      <link>https://asphota.github.io/blog/ccra_upper_arun_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:18:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asphota.github.io/blog/ccra_upper_arun_project/</guid>
      <description>Climate Change Risk Assessment of the Upper Arun Hydropower Project in Nepal The International Hydropower Association (IHA, 2019) published Hydropower Sector Climate Resilience Guide  that offers a methodology for identifying, assessing, and managing climate risks to enhance the resilience of hydropower projects. In this project, we used the guide to assess the climate risks (changes in mean, extremes, and effect on daily operation) to a proposed Upper Arun Hydroelectric Project in Nepal for the World Bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Resiliency of a hydropower project</title>
      <link>https://asphota.github.io/blog/climate_change_risk_analysis_nepal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:18:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asphota.github.io/blog/climate_change_risk_analysis_nepal/</guid>
      <description>Climate Change Risk Analysis of a Hydropower Project in Nepal Hydropower projects face climate change risks due to changes in hydrology with increasing global temperature. To assess the impact on individual hydropower projects, a robustness-based bottom-up approach was introduced known as the Decision Tree Framework in 2015. In collaboration with Deltares and FutureWater, we at the University of Cincinnati analyzed the risks to a hydropower project in Nepal for the World Bank in 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
