<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hydropower on Asphota Wasti</title>
    <link>https://asphota.github.io/tags/hydropower/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hydropower on Asphota Wasti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:18:40 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asphota.github.io/tags/hydropower/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are our hydropower climate resilient?</title>
      <link>https://asphota.github.io/blog/climate_change_and_hydropower_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:18:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asphota.github.io/blog/climate_change_and_hydropower_review/</guid>
      <description>Review of Climate Change Impacts on the Hydropower Sector The United Nations has been organizing global climate summits for over 3 decades now. Almost every country on earth participates in these summits – called COPs – which stands for ‘Conference of the Parties&#39; to work towards a solution to climate change. In the most recent summit, COP26, the participating countries agreed on four main goals. The first goal was to &amp;ldquo;Secure global net-zero by mid-century and keep 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate change risk assessment of a hydropower project</title>
      <link>https://asphota.github.io/blog/ccra_upper_arun_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:18:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asphota.github.io/blog/ccra_upper_arun_project/</guid>
      <description>Climate Change Risk Assessment of the Upper Arun Hydropower Project in Nepal The International Hydropower Association (IHA, 2019) published Hydropower Sector Climate Resilience Guide  that offers a methodology for identifying, assessing, and managing climate risks to enhance the resilience of hydropower projects. In this project, we used the guide to assess the climate risks (changes in mean, extremes, and effect on daily operation) to a proposed Upper Arun Hydroelectric Project in Nepal for the World Bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much does suspended sediment corrode the turbine?</title>
      <link>https://asphota.github.io/blog/short_term_consultant_wb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:18:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asphota.github.io/blog/short_term_consultant_wb/</guid>
      <description>Suspended Sediment Concentration and Turbine Performance of Hydropower Projects In this independent consulting job for the World Bank, I collected suspended sediment and turbine performance data for hydropower projects in Nepal and India.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
